Guide to the KZSU Project South Interviews
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Interviews, 1965
  - Black MFDP - SNCC volunteers and staff, local Mississippi blacks
    - Alma Jean Diller, Negro, female, discussing organizing strikes and Jackson demonstrations and jail, 9005 (side 1), Indianola, Mississippi (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Lee Dilworth, Negro, male, member of ex-com of FDP, 0264-1 (cont'd from tape 0265, sides 1 and 2), Aberdeen, Mississippi (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Ulysses Everett, 0402, Laurel, Mississippi (Box 6, Folder 156)
    - Charles Graves, Negro, male, FDP Ex-com., 0164-1, Dibbee, Mississippi (Box 6, Folder 157)
    - Victoria Gray, Negro, female, FDP member, ex-com, congressional challenger, 0372, Hattiesburg, Miss [[UNK]-] (Box 6, Folder 158)
    - Lawrence Guyst, Negro, male, FDP: Chairman of party 0305 and 0306, Jackson, Miss. (Box 6, Folder 159)
    - Fannie Lou Hamer, Negro, female, FDP: member of ex. com. and one of the three women challengers, 0491-1, Ruleville, Miss. (Box 6, Folder 160)
    - Aaron E. Henry, Negro, male, FDP: member of ex. com NAACP: state Chairman, 0361 (sides 1 and 2), Clarksdale, Mississippi (Box 6, Folder 161)
    - Bobby James, Negro, male, FDP: Secretary of Batesville co-op, 0324-1, 0252 (side 2), 0324 (sides 1 and 2), Batesville, Mississippi (Box 6, Folder 162)
    - Mr. Jefferson, Negro, male, 0422, Laurel, Miss. (Box 6, Folder 163)
    - Willie Johnson, Negro, male, SNCC staff, former project leader of FDP in Vicksburg, Miss. (Box 6, Folder 164)
    - Rev. J.C. Killingsworth, Negro, male, minister, FDP: local leader, 0360, 0364, Stonewall, Miss. (Box 7, Folder 165)
    - Robert Miles, Negro, male, FDP leader, member of Ex. Com., 0253, Batesville, Mississippi (Box 7, Folder 166)
    - Mrs. Hazel Palmer, Negro, female, FDP: member of ex. com. and head of Jackson office, 0490, Jackson, Mississippi (Box 7, Folder 167)
    - Alvin F. Poussaint, Negro, male, 0408 (sides 1 and 2), Jackson, Mississippi (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - James Read, Negro, male, FDP volunteer, 0483 (sides 1 and 2, 0482, side 2), Philadelphia, Miss. (Box 7, Folder 169)
    - Bobby Talbert, Negro, male, MFDP, 0166 and 9013 (side 1) (Box 7, Folder 170)
    - Judy Ann Thomas, white (Negro father), female, FDP summer volunteer, 9009, (sides 1 and 2) (Box 7, Folder 171)
    - Jonnie Mae Walker, Negro, female, FDP (SNCC) field secretary and local leader, 0481, Hattiesburg, Miss. (Box 7, Folder 172)
    - Cleveland, Williams, Negro, male, President Panola County Farmer's Co-op, 0254-1 (sides 1 and 2), Panola County, Mississippi (Box 7, Folder 173)
    - Pam Egashira, Oriental, female, FDP summer volunteer, 0361 (sides 1 and 2), Stonewall (C larke County), Mississippi (Box 7, Folder 174)
  - Black SCLC - SCOPE volunteers and leaders
    - Frank Bates,Negro, male, Local SCLC, 0270, Crawfordsville, Georgia (Box 7, Folder 175)
    - Bill Randall, Negro, male, NAACP, SCLC and local organizations, 0173, Macon, Georgia (Box 7, Folder 176)
    - Ed Thomas, Negro, male, SCLC volunteer, 0054, Luverne, Alabama (Box 7, Folder 177)
    - Caloin Turner, Negro, male, SCOPE project leader, 0272-7 (side 2), Crawfordsville, Georgia (Box 7, Folder 178)
    - Hosea Williams, Negro, male, SCOPE director of Summer project and right hand man of Martin Luther King, 0337-1 (side 1 and 2), Atlanta, Georgia (Box 7, Folder 179)
  - Black and White leaders
    - Leslie Dunbar, Southern Regional Council, 0338 (sides 1 and 2), Atlanta, Georgia (Box 7, Folder 180)
    - Charles Evers, Negro, male, NAACP state field secretary, 0374-1 (sides 1 and 2), Jackson, Miss. (Box 7, Folder 181)
  - White discussions
    - Bull sessions SCOPE volunteers in Macon, Georgia 0175-76, Discussion of SCLC/s approach, problems of local people (Box 7, Folder 182)
    - Group Interview, SCOPE, 0191-0192, 0196 (Box 7, Folder 183)
    - Post demonstration discussion - SCOPE, 0198-0199 (Box 8, Folder 184)
    - SCOPE volunteer reactions to incidents on tapes 0198-0199 (Box 8, Folder 185)
    - Group Interview - SCOPE, 0202 (sides 1 and 2), Columbia, South Carolina (Box 8, Folder 186)
    - Discussion with two CORE workers, 0204, Homer, La. (Box 8, Folder 187)
    - Discussion with two male white CORE volunteers, 0205-1, Homer, Louisiana (Box 8, Folder 188)
    - Discussion with members of Student Liberal Federation at Louisiana State University, 0215 (Box 8, Folder 189)
    - Bull session, MFDP, Mileston, Mississippi, 0415, 0400, 0420, 0421, 0423 (Box 8, Folder 190)
  - Black discussions
    - Local people, Jackson, Mississippi, 0040 (Box 8, Folder 191)
    - James Phipps, George Jones, 0042, Mt. Beulah, Miss. (Box 8, Folder 192)
    - David Noflin, A. Gilmore, Sampson Gilmore, local Negro telling of integrating a restaurant, 0128, St. Francesville, Louisiana (Box 8, Folder 193)
    - West Batesville Co-op meeting, Cleveland Williams, 0316-0317 (Box 8, Folder 194)
    - Local People, Jackson, Mississippi - just returned from Washington assembly of Unrepresented People, 0340 (Box 8, Folder 195)
    - Discussion with local woman who housed volunteers, 0401 (Box 8, Folder 196)
    - Interviews a Laurel office, 0403, Laurel, Miss. (Box 8, Folder 197)
  - Meetings
    - CORE and Bogalusa Civic and Voters' League, July 7, 1965, 0104-0103 (Box 8, Folder 198)
    - CORE Bogalusa meeting, July 8, 1965, 0103 (side 2) (Box 8, Folder 199)
    - CORE meeting, Bogalusa, July 9, 1965, 0108 (side 2) (Box 8, Folder 200)
    - CORE Mass Meeting, Bogalusa, Louisiana, July 10, 1965, Ebeneezer Baptist Church, 0047 (sides 1 and 2), Charles Simms - Head of Deacons, James Farmer, ex. Director, CORE (Box 8, Folder 201)
    - MFDP, Lawrence Guyot, Ed King discussing Mississip voter ammendment at Tougloo College, 0041 (Box 8, Folder 202)
    - MFDP morning Star Baptist Church, Jackson, Miss., 0051-0052 (Box 8, Folder 203)
    - MFDP Mass meeting, masonic temple hall, Jackson, Mississippi, 0061 reels 1-4 (0067-0070) (Box 8, Folder 204)
    - Post March meeting, Jackson, Mississippi, Morning Star Baptist Church, 0075, 0076 MFDP (Box 8, Folder 205)
    - Rally - Jackson Demonstration, MFDP, 0080, reels 1 (Box 8, Folder 206)
    - MFDP Mass Meeting, Moringstar Baptist Church, Jackson, Mississippi, 0083 (Box 8, Folder 207)
    - MFDP Mass Meeting, Pearl Street Methodist Church, 0017, Jackson, Mississippi (Box 8, Folder 208)
    - Meeting MFDP: 2nd Congressional District, Batesvil Mississippi, 0208, 0130 (Box 8, Folder 209)
    - Church Service, West Camp U. Church, Batesville, Mississippi, 0322 (sides 1 and 2) (Box 8, Folder 210)
    - Meeting MFDP, Batesville, Mississippi, 0321, 0320, 0391 (Box 8, Folder 211)
    - SCLC conducted mass meeting, Macon, Georgia, 0172 (Box 9, Folder 212)
    - SCLC meeting, Marion, Alabama, Store boycott, voter registration and Negro apathy, 0025-0026 (Box 9, Folder 213)
    - MFDP Orientation sessions, 0132, 0133, 0135, 0136, 0137, 0139, 0140, 0141, 0144, 0144a, Hattiesburg (Box 9, Folder 214)
    - SCOPE (SCLC) Orientation, speakers include: Abernathy, Ralph; Williams, Hosea; and King, Martin Luther, Jr. 0079, 0084, 0085, 0086, 0087, 0088, 0089, 0090, 0091, 0093, 0095, 0096, 0097, 0098, 0099, 0100, 0101, 0432, 0433, 0434, 0435, 0436, 0437 (Box 9, Folder 215)
  - Action tapes transcription
    - Freedom School with Nancy Trutiz, Panola County, Mississippi, MFDP, 0292 (Box 9, Folder 216)
    - Literacy Class, West Como, Mississippi, MFDP, 0356 (Box 9, Folder 217)
    - Registration Canvassing, MFDP, Quitman, Miss. 0362 (Box 9, Folder 218)
    - Freedom School and informal discussions, Belzoni, Miss. 0417 (Box 9, Folder 219)
    - School integrating canvass, Milestone, Miss. 0418, (side 1) (Box 9, Folder 220)
  - Freedom Labor Union (FLU)
    - Mrs. Hawkins at MFDP orientation. 0142 (side 1) (Box 9, Folder 221)
    - Discussion of FLU by Mrs. Carthan and Mrs. Hawkins FDP leaders, 0301 (sides 1 and 2) (Box 9, Folder 222)
    - Interviews and group discussion of FLU, Indianola, Mississippi, 0302 (sides 1 and 2) (Box 9, Folder 223)
    - FLU Meeting, Indianola, Mississippi, 0303 (sides 1 and 2) (Box 9, Folder 224)
    - FLU discussion in Batesville, Miss. 0323 (Box 9, Folder 225)
    - Radio talk by Charles Horowitz on FLU, 0484 (Box 9, Folder 226)
    - Bull Session on FLU, Shaw, Miss. 9008 (Box 9, Folder 227)
    - FLU meeting, Cleveland, Miss. 9010-9011 (Box 9, Folder 228)
  - Deacons for Defense and Justice
    - CORE and the Deacons about the integration of Headstart, 0207, the Deacons of Homer, La. (Box 10, Folder 229)
    - MFDP meeting at which Deacons speak, 0485, 0487 (Box 10, Folder 230)
  - Reports
    - Report on Selma based on interviews and talks with many members of the total society, 0149 (Box 10, Folder 231)
    - Frank Smith discusses his idea for a co-op brick factory, Mt. Beulah, Mississippi, 0409-0410 (Box 10, Folder 232)
  - The White South
    - FBI agent in Shreveport, La., 0206 (side 2) (Box 10, Folder 233)
    - Sheriff Strickland, Joe E., Clay County, 0240 (sides 1 and 2) (Box 10, Folder 234)
    - Panel discussion of pros and cons on the Mississipi amendment to cut down on voter qualifications, WLBT - TV, Jackson, 0304 (Box 10, Folder 235)
    - Klu Klux Klan Meeting, Brandon, Mississippi, speakers: Edward L. McDaniel and Robert Sheldon, 0341, 0342, 0343 (Box 10, Folder 236)
- Addenda, 1972 Nov
  - Release forms signed by the interviewees [in most cases the address is not included]; and informational questionnaires about the person being interviewe which were filled out by the interviewer at the time of the interview. (Box 11)
  - 5"×8" cards containing what appear to be partial transcriptions of the taped interviews. Content also include some IBM punch cards, punched with the names of educational institutions. (Box 12-14)
- Addenda, 1976 Apr
  - Stanford University. Project South Oral Histories [microfiche edition published by the Microfilm Corporation of America and the New York Times] (Box 15)
Appendix: Projects Visited
Alabama - Southern Christian Leadership Conference
Demopolis
Greensboro
Greenville
Luverne
Marion
Midway
Montgomery
Selma (also the SNCC project located there)
Arkansas - Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee
Little Rock - state headquarters
Georgia - Southern Christian Leadership Conference
Atlanta - Southern headquarters of SCLC & SNCC
Crawfordville
Macon
Louisiana - Congress of Racial Equality
Baton Rouge - state headquarters
Bogalusa
Clinton
Ferriday
Greensburg
Homer
Jonesboro
Minden
Monroe
New Orleans project
New Roads
Plaquemine - evaluation session
Shreveport
Southern Regional CORE office
St. Francisville
Tallulah
Waveland, Miss. - orientation
Mississippi - Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party
Batesville
Beasley
Belzoni
Biloxi
Canton
Clarksdale
Cleveland
Greenville
Greenwood
Hattiesburg - orientation
Holly Springs
Indianola
Jackson - state headquarters
Laurel
McComb
Mileston
Mt. Beulah
Natchez
Phela
Philadelphia
Quitman
Ruleville
Shaw
Vicksburg
West Point
Whites
South Carolina - Southern Christian Leadership Conference
Columbia
Orangeburg